BENJAMIN J. HUMBERSTON

bhumberston@gmail.com | 412-608-7523 | www.benhumberston.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer, researcher, and game developer with the goal of creating powerful systems and delightful user experiences. Experience developing both web and cloud-connected desktop applications. Applied research work in computer graphics, VR environments, physics-driven character animation, and machine learning. Passion for building software that is not only high-performance but also maintainable over extended periods.

INTERESTS

- o Computer graphics, game development, and character animation
- o Distributed, cloud-connected, and mobile applications
- o Machine learning and data-driven computing

EDUCATION

MS, Computer Science
Sep. 2014
University of British Columbia
Vancouver, BC

Thesis: *Precision Manipulations Using a Low-Dimensional Haptic Interface* Teaching assistant for courses in functional programming and AI.

BS, Computer Science
May 2009
Cornell University
Ithaca, NY

Computer graphics and game development focus; GPA 3.98

President of digital games club and active in student game development initiative

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Autodesk, Inc.

Sep. 2014 – Present
Pittsburgh, PA

Sep. 2013 – July 2014

Pittsburgh, PA

Developer for ReCap 360 applications and technology (C++, OpenGL, GLSL).

Graduate Assistant in PhD program Carnegie Mellon University

Research on data-driven computing and applications of machine learning to computer graphics (C++, Python, OpenGL, Android).

Software Engineer

Aug. 2009 – Apr. 2011

Electronic Arts (EA 2D studio)

Redwood Shores, CA

Developer on browser-based *Dragon Age Journeys* and social RPG *Dragon Age Legends*. Roles in client (AS3) and server (Java) gameplay systems, AI, animation, optimization, and UI. Lead developer of character animation and turn-based combat systems.

Software Engineering Intern
Electronic Arts (Maxis studio)
Summer 2008
Emeryville, CA

Prototyped gameplay and control features, improved rendering effects, and coordinated audio integration on unreleased expansion for *Spore* franchise.

Software Engineering Intern
Oracle
Summer 2007
Redwood Shores, CA

Profiled CPU and memory performance of e-commerce framework (Java).

SKILLS

- o Computer graphics, rendering, and linear algebra
- Commercial game development for web and desktop titles
- o Threaded, multi-process, and distributed computing
- o Character controllers for physically-based animation
- o Multimodal VR environment design with graphical and haptic rendering
- o Machine learning applications for classification, regression, and data visualization
- o Current tools: C++, Python, OpenGL, GLSL, Qt, Visual Studio
- o Past tools: MATLAB, AS 3.0, C#, Flex, MongoDB, numpy, scikit-learn
- o Development Platforms: Windows, Linux, Android

PUBLICATIONS

- O B. Humberston and D. K. Pai. *Hands On: Interactive Animation of Precision Manipulation and Contact.* Best Paper award, SCA 2015. Los Angeles, CA.
- o M. Stanton, B. Humberston, B. Kase, J. F. O'Brien, K. Fatahalian, A. Treuille. *Self-Refining Games Using Player Analytics*. ACM SIGGRAPH 2014. Vancouver, BC.
- o B. Humberston and D. K. Pai. *Precision Manipulations Using a Low-Dimensional Haptic Interface*. MS thesis, University of British Columbia. Vancouver, 2014